<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Nodejs | Infinite | Squares]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/categories/nodejs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.infinitesquares.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-22T09:03:59+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.infinitesquares.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nurul Arif Setiawan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flatten Node_modules]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/21/flatten-node-modules/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-21T05:45:42+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/21/flatten-node-modules</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you worked with Node.js, you might start notice youd node_modules started to simply nested into the abyss and the path is getting longer and longer. Consider this :</p>

<p><code>/C/Users/ArifSetiawan/Repository/Katch/katch/node_modules/sails/node_modules/grunt-contrib-less/node_modules/less/node_modules/request/node_modules/form-data/node_modules/combined-stream/node_modules/delayed-stream/test/integration/test-handle-source-errors.js</code></p>

<p>Yes, it is a headache to see deeply nested node_modules. You got more headache when you see that there are some duplicated node_modules pop out elsewhere. Well, the headache part is subjective my opinion.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I think <a href="https://www.npmjs.org/">npm</a> is designed to work in fire and forget style, when you install a module, you don&rsquo;t have to think dependencies hell where some modules require one module with different version number. If you install the latest, then other module simply break. You can&rsquo;t control that other modules author might choose to ignore if their modules dependency is updated with breaking changes. The solution is thet each module has its own <code>node_modules</code> and each module in <code>node_modules</code> has its own <code>node_modules</code> and so on.</p>

<p>A while ago, I wrote a Node.js module named <strong>flatten-packages</strong> that will flatten your node_modules into one level and removing all duplicates by aggressiely delete old version when new one is found. You can find the project on <a href="https://github.com/arifsetiawan/flatten">github</a>. There are things to consider when using <strong>flatten-packages</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Your node_modules folder might explode with numbers of previously nested node_modules.</li>
<li>Version changes might break some of your dependency</li>
<li>You might be confused when trying to relate your package.json with exploded node_modules</li>
</ul>


<p>With <code>flatten-packages -i</code> command, you can get summary of your node_modules hierarcy.</p>

<p>Sample <code>flatten-packages -i</code> output</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/flatten_node_modules_small.png" title="Flatten small" alt="Flatten small" /></p>

<p>From 17 modules into 73 modules. I can live with that</p>

<p>Now consider this</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/flatten_node_modules_big.png" title="Flatten big" alt="Flatten big" /></p>

<p>8 layers deep of node_modules with 514 duplicates! If I flatten it, my node_modules folder with explode from 33 modules into 271 modules!</p>

<p>As I have said before, with npm you shouldn&rsquo;t worry about those deeply nested node_modules which cause <a href="https://github.com/joyent/node/issues/6960">Windows issue when filename has more than 260 characters</a> and modules duplicates (514 in above case) that eat up your disk space (disk is cheap now). It&rsquo;s just unlucky for me to work on Windows with ony 10 GB to spare. That what causes my headache.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Know Your Npm]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/20/know-your-npm/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-20T17:19:15+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/20/know-your-npm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.npmjs.org/">NPM (Node Packaged Modules)</a> is indespensable part of <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a> ecosystem. Knowing how to use npm is really important when working on Node.js project. Some of the npm commands :</p>

<ul>
<li><code>npm init</code> &ndash;> create package.json file to start a Node.js project</li>
<li><code>npm install MODULENAME --save</code> &ndash;> install module and save to dependencies in package.json</li>
<li><code>npm install MODULENAME --save-dev</code> &ndash;> install module and save to devDependencies in package.json</li>
<li><code>npm install --production</code> &ndash;> skip devDependencies install</li>
<li><code>npm shrinkwrap</code> &ndash;> lock modules version dependency for the app</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Project Base Template]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/09/nodejs-project-base-template/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-09T15:11:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.infinitesquares.net/blog/2014/09/09/nodejs-project-base-template</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many Node.js starting template, and after working couple times with <a href="http://expressjs.com/">Expressjs</a>, I also ended up creating my own base template. You can check it out <a href="https://github.com/arifsetiawan/node-base">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Base template ideally support your workflow and it has some structure to organize your code. My base template is not meant to be a full fledged framework like <a href="http://sailsjs.org/">sailsjs</a>, it just a bunch of codes that I would like to be readily available when I started a Node.js project. As I work more with Node.js, my base template will be evolving.</p>

<h2>Components</h2>

<ul>
<li>MongoDB as database</li>
<li>Passport to manage authentication with session stored in MongoDB</li>
<li>Formidable for multipart post</li>
<li>Swig as templating engine</li>
<li>Generic MongoDB query</li>
<li>Front end components

<ul>
<li>Bootstrap</li>
<li>Font awesome</li>
<li>jQuery</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
